<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 - Polling</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/19/week-3-polling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/19/week-3-polling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s post, we focus on analyzing polling data, attempting to understand how they can best predict election outcomes. My thanks again to Matthew Dardet for his generous starter code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of this analysis, we focus on polling data from FiveThirtyEight. We began by visualizing the available data from the past several elections, understanding how polling data changes relative to the actual election outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.org/post/2024/09/19/week-3-polling/index_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This data shows the polling averages at various stages of the election, benchmarked against the actual vote share earned by each candidate during that year&amp;rsquo;s election (horizontal lines). This is very likely affected by events occurring during the election cycle and each campaign&amp;rsquo;s response to them. For example, we see a substantial decline in support for Donald Trump around June 2020 - perhaps corresponding to the murder of George Floyd (1).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Elections and the Economy</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/11/week-2-elections-and-the-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/11/week-2-elections-and-the-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s lab, we focus on understanding how well the status of the economy predicts the outcome of an election. In particular, we aim to quantify this uncertainty. My thanks again to Matt Dardet for his generous starter code in section, much of which I have used/adapted here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, we explored how well the economy &lt;em&gt;correlated&lt;/em&gt; with election outcomes by computing the bivariate correlation between quarterly GDP growth and incumbent two-party vote share. We began by reviewing a scatterplot of this data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 - Initial Analyses</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/07/week-1-initial-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/07/week-1-initial-analyses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this first blog post, I conduct some initial analyses of historical American presidential elections. Using &lt;em&gt;popular vote data from 1948-2020 (provided by the course)&lt;/em&gt;, I analyze how competitive elections are and the proportion of states that vote blue/red. My thanks to Matt Dardet for writing much of this code during and before our weekly section, as well as ShuXin Ho for helping me identify latitude/longitude loading bugs in my maps when we were initially building them in section.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
